A better reality awaits.
Ready Player One is a adventure, action, science
fiction film directed by Steven Spielberg.
When the creator of a popular video game system dies, a virtual
contest is created to compete for his fortune.
Parzival / Wade, played by Tye Sheridan.
Art3mis / Samantha, played by Olivia Cooke.
Sorrento, played by Ben Mendelsohn.
Aech / Helen, played by Lena Waithe.
I-R0k (voice), played by T.J. Miller.
Curator / Ogden Morrow, played by Simon Pegg.
Ready Player One is a 2018 American science fiction action film directed by
Steven Spielberg from a screenplay by Ernest Cline and Zak Penn.
Based on Cline's 2011 novel Ready Player One, it stars Tye
Sheridan, Olivia Cooke, Ben Mendelsohn, Lena Waithe, T.J.
Miller, Simon Pegg and Mark Rylance.
The film is set in 2045, where much of humanity uses the OASIS, a
virtual reality simulation, to escape the real world.
Teenage orphan Wade Watts finds clues to a contest that promises ownership of the OASIS to the
winner, and he and his allies try to complete it before an evil corporation can do so.
Development of the film first began in mid-2010 when Warner Bros.
acquired the rights to the book.
In July 2015, Spielberg signed on to direct and produce the
film, with casting commencing in September 2015.
Filming began in England in June 2016 and was completed in September that year.
The visual effects were handled by Industrial Light & Magic, Digital Domain and Territory
Studio, with some pre-visualization work done by The Third Floor, Inc..
As with the novel, many popular culture references appear throughout the film, including those to the Back
to the Future franchise, The Iron Giant, The Shining, King Kong, and the Godzilla franchise.
Ready Player One premiered at South by Southwest in Austin, Texas on March 11, 2018, and
was theatrically released in the United States on March 29, by Warner Bros.
The film received positive reviews from critics, who praised Spielberg's direction, the
visual effects, brisk pacing, and the performances of both Sheridan and Rylance.
It was also a commercial success, grossing over $607 million worldwide against a $155–175 million budget, and earned a nomination for
Best Visual Effects at the 91st Academy Awards, 24th Critics' Choice Awards, and 72nd British Academy Film Awards.
Ready Player One was awarded the title of Best Science Fiction Film at the 45th Saturn Awards,
and a further two Outstanding Achievement Awards from the Visual Effects Society.
A sequel is in development.
The film explores themes of future, based on novel or
book, video game, virtual reality, dystopia.
The tone is thought_provoking.